

Vijayaprabhakar M Web Designer

vijayaprabhakar2208@gmail.com 🖂

10/90, Mettu Street, 85. R . Komarapalayam, Tamilnadu - 637403

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A broad-skilled professional with an experience of 3 years 7 months, in Web / Graphic / UI / Web Designer.

A key component of my success lies in the fact that I never limit myself to a particular technology as a Web and Graphic design skill and hence, I've always embraced new technologies.

WORK EXPERIENCE SPIDER Web India

Web Designer 03rdJune 2020 to 30thApril 2022

Genuine Infotech

Web Designer
04thMay 2022 to Present

- A Web Designer with 3 years 7 months of experience in software development, Using Adobe Photoshop CC,
 DreamweaverCS6, CSS3, HTML5, Java Script, jQuery, Prototype tools In-vision, Figma.
- Currently using Twitter Bootstrap Framework 3 & 4 & 5.
- Strong Visualizing Skills and Good knowledge on Usability.
- Mocked up screen designs using Bootstrap websites. Responsive conversion.
- Ensuring that business requirements and functional specification for the module coded are tested and fulfilled before the code is delivered for integration.
- Proficiency in web and mobile based applications design. Photoshop Prototype and Creating Style Guide.
- · Designing interfaces for Mobile and Tablet.
- Experienced in working with clients and technical team for executing project.
- · Skilled team member and proven ability to maximize the productivity.
- Excellent team player with good communication skills and quick learner.

TOOLS

Prototyping and Graphics

Adobe Photoshop, Figma, Invision app, Stripo create newsletter and email design.

Web Development

HTML, HTML5, CSS3, Less, Sass and JavaScript, jQuery.

Open source tools

Bootstrap Framework 3 & 4 & 5, JQuery UI Plugins, Wordpress.

SKILLS

- · Wireframe and Prototyping
- Mobile App and Web App Template Designing
- Logo Design and Banner Design
- Mailer Template Design
- CSS Coding
- Responsive Web Design.

EDUCATION

Electronics and Communication Engineering

Government college of Engineering, salem

August 2017 - May, 2020 6.7 CGPA

Diplomo in Electronics and Communication

Muthayammal Polytechnic College, Tamilnadu.

HSC

Tamil Nadu - state board

June 2014– April 2015 53.0%

June 2015 - April, 2017 93.0%

SSLC

April 2012- March 2013 73.0%

Tamil Nadu - state board

PROJECTS

Responsibility

- Able to design complex UI screens by using Adobe Photoshop CC, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery.
- Create Web and Mobile Application design.
- Create Prototype and Wireframe design using tools Figma and Invision App.
- Expert in use of PSD to HTML Responsive Conversion and Web page creation (UX).
- Using Twitter Bootstrap 3 & 4 & 5.
- · Fixing cross browser compatibility issues.
- Using Wordpress Framework, as per the mockup html and css responsive implementation.
- Corporate Site, Career Site, e-Learning, e-Commerce Sites, E-Mailers, Newsletters, etc.

Bootstrap Responisve Websites

https://mydolphin.com.au/

https://www.bollywoodfashion.com.au/

https://www.counselingtools.com/

https://www.bates.edu/

https://www.indianb2b.com/

https://wave.vintools.co/

http://wp.revteks.com/

LANGUAGES KNOWN

English, Tamil.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth:

24 February 1999

Marital status:

Single

10/90, Mettu Street, 85. R . Komarapalayam, Tamilnadu - 637403

Portfolio Link:

https://vijayaprabhakar.github.io/webdesigner